You have found a dog!
The dog, known as Canis familiaris, is a very common species around residential areas.
The reason for this is that they are a domestic species,
that is, a species of animal where humans have exerted immense influence over their livelihood
and care over multiple generations, such that the species develops
enabling traits that make them rely more on humans and enhance their social characteristics.
Dogs were first domesticated in Europe, the area around modern-day Germany,
with the process starting at least 14000 years ago.
However, disputed sources point to other, older possibilities, such as Eurasia.
Whatever the case, the dog is recognised as the first animal species to be domesticated.
This long association with humans is due to the symbiotic relationship between the two species.
The nearest living relative of the modern day dog are the species of grey wolf.
They are valued for their plethora of roles, from simple companionship to hunting, herding and other tasks assisting humans.
As of 2013 there are an estimated 700 million dogs, or up to 987 million, in the world.
However, only around 20% of this number truly live in human homes, with the rest remaining feral or communally owned.
Feel free to click the image to learn more about the dog.