You have found a frog!
The frog, known as Anura, is an amphibian species common in the wild all over all the continents in the world.
Different species of frogs can be found in different environments, from tropical to subarctic regions.
However, the majority of species reside in tropical rainforests.
Warty frog species tend to be called toads, but the distinction between frogs and toads is informal, and not scientific.
The oldest fossil of a species from the frog lineage that is known was found in Madagascar, and is dated to 250 million years ago,
with certain techniques indicating up to 265 million years ago instead.
Frog populations have declined dramatically since the 1950s.
More than one-third of frog species are considered to be threatened with extinction,
and more than 120 species are believed to have become extinct since the 1980s.
The causes are difficult to determine, but it is believed that species such as frogs, which have a presence both in water and land,
possess sensitive skin and an intermediate role in the food chain, make for good indicators of an ecosystem’s health.
Furthermore, infectious diseases have since begun spreading amongst frogs, contributing to the given decline.
Feel free to click the image to learn more about the frog.