You have found a koala!
The koala, known as Phascolarctos cinereus, is naturally not a species common over here.
In truth, koala’s are exclusively native to Australia,
leading this animal species to become eponymous with the continent.
Koala’s are arboreal herbivores, that is, a species of animal that has adapted to eating solely plant material,
and which has evolved to move among trees. They are an asocial species,
meaning the members of the species do not regularly remain in contact,
the exception being mothers and their still dependent offspring.
There is a visible distinction in koala populations between the north and south of Australia,
but there is debate on whether these constitute different subspecies.
Historically, the koala was only introduced to Europe recently,
with the first recorded encounter of a koala by a European being dated to 1798,
with illustration and scientific descriptions following within the following century.
Population estimates for the Koala are similarly disputed, and efforts to detect and count koalas are difficult
as they remain hidden from potential predators such as humans.
The species is, however, considered Vulnerable.
Feel free to click the image to learn more about the koala.